paydaybank.co.uk 2014-02-14

# Privacy Policy

Payday Bank is a trading name of Money Gap Group Limited. Any use of "we", "our" etc refers to this party. We are committed to preserving and respecting your privacy.

The following information covers: 

  * The Data Protection Act
  * How we collect information
  * How we use your information
  * How we protect that information
  * Cookies and how to remove them
  * Disclosure of your information
  * Fraud Prevention
  * Your Rights
  * Further information and contact

##  The Data Protection Act

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998, we are the data controller. We are a company incorporated in England and Wales with Company No. 06617413 and our registered office is 28-32 Wellington Road, London, NW8 9SP. Our data protection register is #Z1696368.

This policy only applies to the collection of your data by us and those we authorise. We may link to third party websites that have their own privacy policy. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies, so please check them before submitting any personal data.

##  Information we collect

Almost all websites gather information about you when you go to them to some degree or other. We don't collect anything scary, as the way we do business is pretty simple. We may collect and use the following data about you: 

  * Information about your visits to our site, and which pages you visited. This is partially so we can make improvements.
  * Your loan application information. This is partially to prevent fraudulent information.
  * A record of any contact you have with us, either by phone, email, online chat or post.
  * Details of transactions you carry through our website and fulfilment of your orders.
  * Decisions made by lenders with regards to your application.

##  How we use your information:

  * To carry out business, including our obligations that arise from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To provide information, products and services you request
  * To process applicationsand keep them secure
  * To monitor how people use each page of our website and service, in order to improve it.
  * To notify you about our services and special offers we think you will find valuable. This will only happen where you have consented to be contacted for these purposes. Anything we send will have information that tells you how to unsubscribe as well. If you don't want to receive anything from us, please email us at [ customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk.](mailto:customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk).
  * We send it to our lenders in order that they can make lending decisions, and also conduct identity verification, credit checking, fraud prevention and debt collection where necessary.
  * To evaluate the effectiveness of our marketing of our website and statistical analysis.

Your details may be passed on to third parties involved in the lending process, including debt management companies and credit rating agencies. Some third parties may contact you for marketing purposes. They will have their own privacy policy and you will need to contact them separately if you want to be removed from their marketing information. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you via email, telephone or SMS for re-marketing purposes. Unless you opt out of future marketing campaigns when you apply with us, we may follow up your application with a courtesy call from one of our Customer Services team to see how you found the process and to offer any further assistance if required.

##  How we protect that information

As part of the lending process, your data may be transferred or stored in locations outside the European Economic Area. Staff from areas outside of the European Economic Area may process your data in order to fulfil your order, process your payment details and provide your support services, amongst other duties. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy at all times. We store all and any information you provide to us on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology to ensure the maximum protection we can provide.

##  Cookies and how to remove them

The way we track information about people who visit our site is by using cookies. This information includes your IP address, operating system and browser type, in order for us to learn aggregate information. This is never used to identify any individual. It also allows us to present you with a consistent experience with our website, and also to use web analytic tools to see how our sites are used in order to improve them. 

Cookies are small pieces of data created when you visit a website and are stored in the cookies directory on your computer. They do not give us any access to your computer and cannot be used to identify an individual user. They're used by many websites.

Cookie  |  Name  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
Essential site cookies  |  ASP.NET_SessionId  |  This cookie is an online notification form cookie, and is essential for the online quick apply form to operate. It is set only for those people using that and is deleted when you close your browser. For more information, Visit the Microsoft website   
|  pdbREF  |  This allows us to see where you accessed the site from, in order that we can monitor and improve our advertising, and so that we can accurately recompense advertisers and affiliates. For more information, Visit the Microsoft website   
Live Chat  |  LivepersonID  |  This saves a limited amount of session and visitor information in order to identify returning visitors by saving LivePerson-specific data such as visitor ID, last chat date, etc. The cookies do not contain any private customer data, or any data which would be accessible or useful outside of LivePerson.   
|  HumanclickACTIVE  
HumanclickKey  
HumanClickSiteContainerID+39923063  |  These allow us to log and respond to livechat conversations, and are used in a similar way to call centre phone conversations being recorded. This is for the protection of both parties involved in the conversation.   
Google Analytics  |  _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  |  These are Google Analytics cookies, which collect information, in an anonymous form, about how visitors use our site, which pages they visited, where they come from, and the number of visitors to our site.Click here for an overview of privacy at Google   
ClickTale  |  WRIgnore WRUID  |  These are ClickTale cookies, which collect information, in an anonymous form, about how visitors use our site. We use this to improve our site designs.Click here for an overview of privacy at Click Tale   
  
If you would prefer not to use cookies, you can opt out of it by changing your browser settings. It should only take a few simple steps.

Just go to “Tools” on your internet browser. On some browsers, this may be an icon of a spanner or gears. 

Then go to “Options”, “Preferences” or “Settings”, depending on the browser you are using. 

The cookies setting will be either in “Privacy”, “Advanced” or “Under the hood”, depending on the browser. 

You will then be able to select your settings as required. 

##  Disclosure of your information

There are limited scenarios where we would ever pass on your data to a third party. These are: 

  * To prospective lenders to consider whether to make a loan to you. This may, as described earlier, involve credit and identity checking, and may involve third parties as appropriate to that end.
  * To law enforcement agencies. This is if there is ever any reason to suspect fraudulent information has been used, or identity theft. This is primarily to protect your privacy and data, in case anyone ever tries to apply with your information.
  * If we sell or buy any business or assets, or if we are acquired by a third party, in which case we may disclose data to prospective sellers or buyers of such business or assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use, and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of Money Gap Group Limited, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We may also share your information with third parties not listed above where you have given your consent or where we are required or permitted to by any applicable law.

## Fraud Prevention

If false or inaccurate information is provided, including in relation to a person's identity and fraud is suspected or identified, details about this information, including customer Personal Data, will be passed to fraud prevention agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent and detect crime, fraud and money laundering, for example when: checking details on applications for credit and credit related and other facilities; managing credit and credit related accounts or other facilities; recovering debt; checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; and checking details of job applicants and employees. We and other organisations may access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies. For further details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies please contact us as described at the end of this Privacy Policy.

##  Your Rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will inform you (by way of our privacy policy and terms and conditions) if we intend to use your data for such purposes. 

You can exercise your right to be removed from any marketing lists by contacting us at [customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk.](mailto:customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk) By unsubscribing from our service, you will be opting out of any of our marketing. You will need to contact any third parties separately. 

You have the right to access information we hold about you. If you would like to exercise this right, just email us and ask. It may be subject to a £10 fee to meet our costs in providing you with the information.

Any changes we make to our privacy policy will be posted on this page. Where appropriate, we will contact you by email. 

You can contact us either by email or post.[customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk.](mailto:customer.support@paydaybank.co.uk) Data Protection Compliance Officer Money Gap Group Limited  
28-32 Wellington Road  
NW8 9SP
